<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TutsWiki Beta</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/</link><description>Recent content on TutsWiki Beta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutswiki.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/python/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/python/introduction/</guid><description>This Google Trends analysis shows how the interest of Python worldwide scaled up above all other Object-Oriented Programming languages in the last few years. Almost every industry worldwide is using Python somehow due to its wide range of applications and easy to understand syntax. So, learning Python would make you a proficient software developer who is job-ready and can apply his/her skills to solve real-world problems.
Another great reason for learning Python is it’s large Open Source community.</description></item><item><title>Classes &amp; Objects</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/class-object/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/class-object/</guid><description>Objects Java is an object-oriented language meaning it follows the object-oriented programming (OOPS) paradigm. The OOPS principle looks at any problem as an interaction between various objects. This, in turn, helps us to solve real-world problems easily because most of it involves objects. Objects are described by their intrinsic properties ( in coding terms some base data ) and how they can interact within the object and also with other objects ( in coding terms some functionality over the data ).</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/introduction/</guid><description>What is R? R is a programming language that is gaining its importance in software development, machine learning and data science. R is free and open source software under GNU General public license and pre-compiled binary versions and libraries are also provided for various operating systems like MAC, Linux and Windows. R provides a software environment for Statistical Modeling of data, Exploratory Data Analysis, Graphics Representation and Reproducible Researches.</description></item><item><title>Insertion Sort</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/insertion-sort/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/insertion-sort/</guid><description>Now when there are sorting algorithms already available like Merge Sort and Quick Sort which can sort a large number of elements in quick time and that too efficiently in most of the cases, we still might require to rely on other sorting techniques in some cases. Today we will discuss one such sorting technique called Insertion Sort. Insertion sort is one of the easiest and efficient sorting algorithms that is a comparison based sorting technique.</description></item><item><title>Constructors</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/constructors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/constructors/</guid><description>Object Initialization We know that in Java classes are blueprints and objects are the actual entities created by following the design of the blueprint. To create an object we need to initialize it or in simpler terms assign resources like memory, initialize instance variables, load methods, etc. If we don&amp;rsquo;t do this Java assigns the object a null value on the declaration of the object. In Java, we use the new keyword to initialize an object whose class/type is not of the primitive types.</description></item><item><title>Installing R and RStudio in Windows &amp; Linux</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/install-env-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/install-env-setup/</guid><description>R is a very popular and most interactive programming language and has been an important toolbox for Data Scientists and Business Analysts. To work and create projects on R, you just need to install two important tools– R and RStudio. Both of these software work in parallel to create various projects and Markdown Documents in R.
Installing R to a local computer consists of various easy steps. The steps for installation of R vary with different operating systems like Windows, Linux and MacOS.</description></item><item><title>Wrapper Class in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/wrapper-class/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/wrapper-class/</guid><description>What is a Wrapper Class? As the name suggests, a wrapper class is used to wrap a primitive data type like int, float, char etc. The wrapper class provides the functionality to encapsulate (wrap) a primitive data type to enable them to use as Objects.
Each primitive data type has a corresponding Wrapper class.
Wrapper classes are provided by the java.lang package.
Primitive Type Wrapper Class Primitive Type Wrapper Class boolean Boolean char Character byte Byte short Short int Integer long Long float Float double Double Example void wrapperClassExample1(){ Integer int1 = new Integer(1); // Deprecated since, Java 9 System.</description></item><item><title>Serialization in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/serialization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/serialization/</guid><description>What is Serialization? Serialization is the mechanism to convert an object into a sequence of bytes so that it could be used in any external process like sending an object via a network or saving in memory. The created sequence of bytes will keep the information that is stored in the object as well as information of Object type and structure, to recreate it again when needed. The mechanism of recreating the object from these sequence of bytes is called Deserialization.</description></item><item><title>Decorators in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/python/decorators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/python/decorators/</guid><description>Have you ever heard about Gift wrappings? Exactly, those which we do on the presents to be gifted. Decorators in Python are nothing but the Gift Wrapping but for functions and classes. In this tutorial, we will deep dive into the implementation of decorators on functions. But before you get into the topic, you should have a proper understanding of functions in Python. Assuming that you have, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.</description></item><item><title>Exceptions in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/python/exceptions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/python/exceptions/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we will be learning about Exceptions. So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
What is an Exception? The very first question that pops up in our minds.
An Exception is an unexpected problem or issue that alters the normal flow of execution.
What is an Exception in Python? Exception in Python is an event that occurs at runtime which disrupts the flow of execution of a program and terminates it abnormally if left unhandled.</description></item><item><title>Exceptions in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/exceptions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/exceptions/</guid><description>Exceptions An exception in java is defined as an unwanted or unexpected event, which arises at the time of execution of a program i.e. at run time which disturbs the normal flow or working of our program.
For better understanding, consider the following scenario where you have planned to watch a movie in a nearby theater and you got ready and departed from your house but in the mid-way, your vehicle got punctured and for reaching your destination you took a taxi.</description></item><item><title>Exception Handling in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/python/exception-handling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/python/exception-handling/</guid><description>Now that we have knowledge of Exceptions and its types, the question arises,
How do we handle exceptions so that flow of our program does not stop abruptly?
Well, for that Python Exception Handling comes to our rescue.
Exception Handling in Python Python provides us try, raise, except and finally blocks for handling raised exceptions properly. Let us understand each of them using an example.
try and except try: x = int(input(&amp;#34;Enter an integer: &amp;#34;)) except ValueError as te: print(&amp;#34;Exception Occured:&amp;#34;,te) Output:</description></item><item><title>Exception Handling</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/exception-handling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/exception-handling/</guid><description>Exception handling is the facility provided by Java to handle all the unwanted event or exception that arises in our program to maintain the normal flow of our code. Whenever there is an exception, the method in which the exception occurs will create an object and that object will store three things:
Exception name: It stores the class name which can handle the occurred exception. Description: It describes what type of exception has occurred.</description></item><item><title>throw and throws</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/throw-throws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/throw-throws/</guid><description>In the previous tutorial, we learned how to handle an exception using try and catch block. Now we will learn how exception handling is done using throw and throws keyword.
throw keyword The keyword throw is employed to throw an exception explicitly. It is mainly used to throw custom exceptions or user-defined exceptions. It is placed inside the method.
Syntax throw new ExceptionClassName(&amp;#34;Message&amp;#34;); JVM or method does not make the exception object like it used to do before.</description></item><item><title>finally</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/finally/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/finally/</guid><description>In the previous tutorial, we learned how to handle an exception using throw and throws keywords. Now we will learn about finally block.
finally finally is the block that will always get executed irrespective of the fact whether the exception is handled or not.
Syntax try () { //code that might produce exception} catch(Exception e) { //handle exception } finally { //code that always gets executed } We can also have finally block without catch block.</description></item><item><title>Lambda Expressions in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/lambda-expressions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/lambda-expressions/</guid><description>1. Lambda Expressions 1.1 Introduction Lambda expression is the fundamental approach to functional programming in Java. It is an anonymous function which doesn’t belong to any class nor does it have a name. It provides a concise way to show a method or interface. Provides implementation of functional interface. 1.2 Syntax Parameter(s) -&amp;gt; body of expression
1.3 Characteristics Optional type declaration - Declaration of parameter type is not required.</description></item><item><title>Regular Expressions in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/regex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/regex/</guid><description>1.1 Introduction Regular Expression in simple terms is a special sequence of symbols and alphanumeric characters that defines a search pattern.
1.2 Uses These are used to describe what you are looking for when you search for data in text, article etc.
It is used for Data Validation e.g. checking if the user has inserted a valid e-mail address or not while registering in a website. It is used for Data Scraping/Web scraping e.</description></item><item><title>SDKMan - Installing Multiple Versions of Java in Same Machine</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/sdkman-installing-multiple-versions-java-same-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/sdkman-installing-multiple-versions-java-same-machine/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world technology is evolving at a very high pace, everyday something new comes in the market. Same is the case with computer languages, new languages are coming day by day and even newer versions of old languages are being released.
For example, we have many versions of Java like Java 7, Java 8, Java 11 and many more.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s suppose you&amp;rsquo;re currently working on a project in Java 8 but you want to use the new features which are provided by Java 11 on the same machine or make a new project by using some other version of Java.</description></item><item><title>Writing and Reading JSON config file in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-json-config-file-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-json-config-file-in-python/</guid><description>A Config short for Configuration file is a file that stores information such as parameters, settings, configurations, and preferences of an application.
Config files are simply plain text files with .config, .ini, .json, .xml, .yaml file extensions among others that can be created, viewed or edited using any text editor.
For example, the Web.config file in Microsoft ASP.NET MVC application contains configuration information that controls the working of the application.</description></item><item><title>Writing and Reading XML config file in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-xml-config-file-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-xml-config-file-in-python/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve already covered .ini, .json and .yaml in below articles, in this article we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on .xml config files.
.ini file in Python .json file in Python .yaml file in Python Reading and Writing config data to XML file in Python XML, or eXtensible Markup Language is a markup language just like HTML that can be interpreted by both humans and computers easily. XML does not have predefined tags.</description></item><item><title>Writing and Reading YAML config file in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-yaml-config-file-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-yaml-config-file-in-python/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve already covered .ini, .json and .xml in below articles, in this article we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on .yaml config files.
.ini file in Python .json file in Python .xml file in Python Reading and Writing config data to YAML file in Python YAML or YAML Ain't Markup Language is a case sensitive and human-friendly data serialization language used mainly for configurations.
For reading and writing to the YAML file, we first need to install the PyYAML package by using the following command.</description></item><item><title>Annotations in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/annotations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/annotations/</guid><description>1. Java Annotation 1.1 Introduction Java annotations are a special type of comments which embed instruction for Java compiler. These embed instructions for code processing tools. These also embed metadata which are read at runtime by Java compiler. 1.2 Built-In Annotations @Override: This annotation makes sure to tell the compiler that the method in subclass should override the method of the superclass. If it does not override that method then it gives a compile-time error.</description></item><item><title>Top 4 Must Have Skills For A Project Manager</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/project-manager-must-have-skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/project-manager-must-have-skills/</guid><description>According to studies conducted by PWC, 77% of the high performing companies realise the importance of project management but only 2.5% are able to complete all the projects. Despite having all team members on board, the low productivity rate has to be explained by the Project Manager, who couldn&amp;rsquo;t plan the right course of actions or overlooked the breakdown in communications.
As simple and self-explanatory the term Project Manager sounds, his/her duty involves lots of multi-tasking and diversified knowledge in numerous areas.</description></item><item><title>How to setup and access QuestDB using Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/setup-access-questdb-python-notebook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/setup-access-questdb-python-notebook/</guid><description>What is QuestDB? It is a tremendously fast NewSQL database which is avaiable as Open source software under Apache 2.0 license. It is basically like a superset of a SQL database (with added features and support for time-varying data or event data). It is made with the prime focus on performance.
What makes QuestDB stand apart from other databases? SIMD aggregations: QuestDB uses vectorized operations to perform many operations on only one CPU procedure which makes it do tasks in a must faster and efficient way.</description></item><item><title>How to access to internet on Linux using Android Tethering</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/access-internet-on-linux-using-android-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/access-internet-on-linux-using-android-tethering/</guid><description>What is Tethering? It&amp;rsquo;s been over 30 years since the World Wide Web was introduced to the world. Over time, the internet took its toll and now has roughly around 45 million web pages compared to 10,000 websites earlier. We really do have come a long way.
Emerging from the primitive world of 2G signals we are now living in the era where mostly every device has an internet connection and if not of its own, gets one from another system.</description></item><item><title>How to install software in Linux (RPM/DEB systems)</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/install-software-linux-yum-rpm-apt-dpkg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/install-software-linux-yum-rpm-apt-dpkg/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering packages, package managers and how to find, install and remove software for most popular Linux distributions.
Package Typically when you install software in a Linux system you do so with a package. A package is just a collection of files that make up an application. Additionally, a package contains data about the application as well as any steps required to successfully install and remove that application.</description></item><item><title>Writing and Reading config files in Angular</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-angular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-angular/</guid><description>Every app has some configurations to load. The most common is environment configurations which are required when you have multiple environments - local, dev, qa, uat and prod. Well this article will tell you where to store configurations and how to read them in Angular.
Storing config in Angular Let&amp;rsquo;s say we need to store the baseUrl of our app. Where do you think this should be added? There is a defined place for storing config in Angular and you should make most use of it.</description></item><item><title>Approximating Randomness</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/approximating-randomness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/approximating-randomness/</guid><description>Generating random numbers from computers is essential to the development of certain kinds of software. Anything from modelling the environment, to a lottery machine, to determining the value of loot in a chest in an RPG, will require random number generation. At first it may seem strange that computers, which are capable of producing massive amounts of digits in a short time, would not be able to produce random numbers. The difficulty is that the computers we use, are constructed specifically to follow logical steps deterministically, so to generate numbers that are truly random from a system like our computers is virtually impossible.</description></item><item><title>How to convert a Python script to module</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/convert-python-script-to-module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/convert-python-script-to-module/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s common to create small scripts which we want to combine into a larger script. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to copy and paste the code. We want to leave the working code in one file and use it in multiple places. Often we want to combine elements from multiple files to create more sophisticated scripts.
The problem we have is that when we import a script it actually starts running. This is generally not what we expect when we import a script so that we can reuse it.</description></item><item><title>Grunt Tutorial with Live Example</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/grunt-tutorial-example/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/grunt-tutorial-example/</guid><description>So, what is this thing called Grunt and how can it help you?
From the grunt documentation:
“A task-based command line build tool for JavaScript projects”
This means one simple thing. Stop repeating yourself and let Grunt do stuff for you. The Grunt ecosystem is constantly growing and being improved by open source contributors.
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Plugins You can find plugins for almost everything.</description></item><item><title>noprocrast</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/noprocrast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/noprocrast/</guid><description>I wrote a command line script called noprocrast. This script updates /etc/hosts to make distracting websites unreachable from my machine:
sudo cp /etc/noprocrast_hosts /etc/hosts The corresponding /etc/noprocrast_hosts:
127.0.0.1 localhost db001 db002 db003 db004 web030 web048 255.255.255.255 broadcasthost ::1 localhost fe80::1%lo0 localhost 127.0.0.1 news.ycombinator.com 127.0.0.1 reddit.com www.reddit.com 127.0.0.1 twitter.com 127.0.0.1 nytimes.com www.nytimes.com In case I really need to visit one of these sites, I use the following procrast script:
sudo cp /etc/procrast_hosts /etc/hosts echo `date` &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.</description></item><item><title>How to fix sudo node command not found error</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/how-to-fix-sudo-node-command-not-found-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/how-to-fix-sudo-node-command-not-found-error/</guid><description>Getting permission errors when installing a module?
Are &amp;lsquo;sudo: node: command not found&amp;rsquo; errors taking away your precious sleeping hours?
How to fix? You have to remove any trace of node on your system, and reinstall it. It will soothe your pain:
echo &amp;#39;export PATH=$HOME/local/bin:$PATH&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc . ~/.bashrc mkdir ~/local &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ~/node-latest-install &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ~/node-latest-install curl https://nodejs.org/dist/node-latest.tar.gz | tar xz --strip-components=1 ./configure --prefix=~/local &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install curl https://npmjs.org/install.sh | sh rm -rf ~/node-latest-install You are one/two steps/commands away from success.</description></item><item><title>Yet another lousy monad tutorial</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/yet-another-lousy-monad-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/yet-another-lousy-monad-tutorial/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of monads, but I understand them. They&amp;rsquo;re not rocket science. Let me try to write a monad tutorial that would&amp;rsquo;ve helped my past self understand what the fuss was about. I like concrete explanations that start with practical examples, without any annoying metaphors, and especially without any Haskell code. So here&amp;rsquo;s five examples that have something in common:
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).</description></item><item><title>A Deeper Look at Ruby's Enumerable</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/ruby-enumerable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/ruby-enumerable/</guid><description>Have you ever needed to load a VERY large file in ruby? No I don’t mean your 500 line rails model. I mean a several gig binary or text file.
Try it. Watch your machine become unresponsive. Cry a little inside. Then reach for enumerable.
Ruby’s Enumerable module gives you a way of iterating over collections in a lazy manner, loading only what you need, when you need it. But it gives us so much more than that.</description></item><item><title>A REST API in Clojure</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/rest-api-in-clojure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/rest-api-in-clojure/</guid><description>Clojure is one of the most interesting new languages targeting the JVM. Initially only the JVM, in the meantime it is also available for JavaScript. Essentially, you can write Clojure and either execute it as Java program or JavaScript program, of course each flavor has its unique features as well.
Clojure is a Lisp, thus the syntax may be foreign, but it is really, really easy since there are very few syntactic variations.</description></item><item><title>Abstract classes and interfaces in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/abstract-classes-and-interfaces-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/abstract-classes-and-interfaces-in-python/</guid><description>Abstract base classes and interfaces are entities that are similar in purpose and meaning. Both the first and second are a peculiar way of documenting the code and help to limit (decouple) the interaction of individual abstractions in the program (classes).
Python is a very flexible language. One facet of this flexibility is the possibilities provided by metaprogramming. And although abstract classes and interfaces are not represented in the core of the language, the former were implemented in the standard abc module, and the latter in the Zope project (the zope.</description></item><item><title>How Deep Learning Helped Reducing Variability in Cardiovascular Imaging</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/deep-learning-cardiovascular-imaging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/deep-learning-cardiovascular-imaging/</guid><description>Bay Labs, a San Francisco-based medical technology company which focuses on using artificial intelligence to improve cardiovascular imaging, has released a new software EchoMD AutoEF. It is being claimed that this software will help to reduce the variability in cardiovascular imaging.
The software uses deep learning techniques to accurately calculate the left ventricular ejection fraction.
What is Ejection Fraction? During each pumping cycle of our heart, it contracts and relaxes.</description></item><item><title>Google Engineers Boycott Against Security Tool for Military</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/google-engineers-boycott-security-tool-military/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/google-engineers-boycott-security-tool-military/</guid><description>A group of 9 cloud engineers at Google has refused to work on a project called air-gap due to which Google may lose a deal worth $10 billion. Google needs air-gap if it has to do some sensitive work with government agencies involving sensitive data (obviously military implications there). So this group of 9 basically just said they weren&amp;rsquo;t gonna do it. About 10-12 employees have resigned so far as part of this work strike.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy Node.js app on Google App Engine</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/nodejs-google-app-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/nodejs-google-app-engine/</guid><description>Google App Engine is a part of the Google Cloud Suite which provides a cloud platform for developers where they can develop and host their apps. It provides easily configurable, fast and secure programming environments/tools with the help of which developers can setup a development environment in just a few minutes. Therefore developers don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about configuring the environment, they can just focus on writing code. It supports all the popular programming languages Java, PHP, Node.</description></item><item><title>What's new in Angular 6 (Features List)</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</guid><description>Angular 6 is out with all new features. It is a major release in which Angular team has synchronized many of the important framework packages to make most out of cross compatibility. All the major framework packages like @angular/core, @angular/compiler, @angular/common etc., are reworked and released as version 6.0.0. Below is the list of major changes in Angular 6, let&amp;rsquo;s explore them one by one.
Angular 6 Features: New CLI commands ng update ng add Referencing providers Angular Elements Angular Material + CDK Components Tree Badge Bottom-Sheet Overlay Starter Components Dashboard Side-Nav Datatable Library Support CLI Workspaces RxJS v6 Long Term Support ng update A new command is introduced in Angular CLI which analyzes package.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Alternatives (Free, Paid, Self-Hosted)</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/github-alternatives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/github-alternatives/</guid><description>The trending news of yesterday was the acquisition of GitHub (the world&amp;rsquo;s leading software development platform) by Microsoft. This is a great deal for Microsoft which might put it in the position it was about 10 years ago in the software market. But a lot of open-source fans are unhappy with this.
A couple of years ago Microsoft was anti-open-source.
&amp;ldquo;Open source is an intellectual-property destroyer. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine something that could be worse than this for the software business and the intellectual-property business.</description></item><item><title>What is the use of yield in Python?</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/what-is-the-use-of-yield-in-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/what-is-the-use-of-yield-in-python/</guid><description> References What does the “yield” keyword do in Python? Yield expressions</description></item><item><title>Difference between append and extend in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/append-vs-extend-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/append-vs-extend-python/</guid><description>append and extend are list methods in Python which can be used to combine multiple lists. But what is the difference between them? When should you use one over another, let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
The official documentation describes them as:
list.append(x): Add an item to the end of the list; equivalent to a[len(a):] = [x].
list.extend(L): Extend the list by appending all the items in the given list; equivalent to a[len(a):] = L.</description></item><item><title>How to print on same line with print in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/print-same-line-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/print-same-line-python/</guid><description>In Python, when you use the print function, it prints a new line at the end.
For example:
print &amp;#34;This is some line.&amp;#34; print &amp;#34;This is another line.&amp;#34; Output:
This is some line. This is another line. What if you want to avoid the newline and want to print both statements on same line? Well, there are 2 possible solutions.
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Add comma at the end of print print &amp;#34;This is some line.</description></item><item><title>Writing and Reading config files in Python</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-python/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure you must be aware about the importance of configuration files. Config files help creating the initial settings for any project, they help avoiding the hardcoded data.
Imagine if you migrate your server to a new host and suddenly your application stops working, now you have to go through your code and search/replace IP address of host at all the places. Config file comes to the rescue in such situation.</description></item><item><title>How to run a Python module as script?</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/run-module-as-script-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/run-module-as-script-python/</guid><description>Suppose you have a module named mymath.py, which has a couple of functions. You can import this module in your script and call these functions.
def int_sum(a, b): print a+b def some_other_function(): pass But, what if you want to run the module itself as a script?
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Well, if you want to use a Python module as script then you just have to use the conditional for __name__.</description></item><item><title>What is if __name__ == "__main__" in Python?</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/if-name-main-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/if-name-main-in-python/</guid><description>If you are new to Python then you may have noticed if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot; line in some python codes.
You may be wondering:
What does that mean? What purpose does it serve? I don&amp;rsquo;t see it in all Python codes, so when should I use it exactly? Can you give me some examples? Let me try to explain the above to you.
In Python all modules have some built-in attributes.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 1 - Reading from a CSV</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter1/</guid><description># Render our plots inline %matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) # Make the graphs a bit prettier plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 5) (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); 1.1 Reading data from a CSV file You can read data from a CSV file using the read_csv function. By default, it assumes that the fields are comma-separated.
We&amp;rsquo;re going to be looking some cyclist data from Montréal.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2 - Selecting and finding desired data</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter2/</guid><description># The usual preamble %matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt # Make the graphs a bit prettier, and bigger pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) # This is necessary to show lots of columns in pandas 0.12. # Not necessary in pandas 0.13. pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.width&amp;#39;, 5000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;, 60) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 5) We&amp;rsquo;re going to use a new dataset here, to demonstrate how to deal with larger datasets. This is a subset of the of 311 service requests from NYC Open Data.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 - Filtering dataframes</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter3/</guid><description># The usual preamble %matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np # Make the graphs a bit prettier, and bigger pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 5) # This is necessary to show lots of columns in pandas 0.12. # Not necessary in pandas 0.13. pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.width&amp;#39;, 5000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;, 60) Let&amp;rsquo;s continue with our NYC 311 service requests example.
complaints = pd.read_csv(&amp;#39;311-service-requests.csv&amp;#39;) (adsbygoogle = window.</description></item><item><title>Heap Sort</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/heap-sort/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/heap-sort/</guid><description>Sorting as you might already know is basically an algorithm that is used for arranging elements of a list in a certain order. (Usually ascending or descending). Sorting is one of the most important categories of algorithms, it can significantly reduce the complexity of problems, and is generally used for efficient searching.
There are an ample number of sorting algorithms available like the Bubble sort, Selection sort, Insertion sort, Merge sort, Quick sort, Heap sort, Counting sort and more.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction Bjarne Stroustrup, a C and Simula67 enthusiast, thought of combining the best of both the languages, and subsequently, C++ emanated at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Laboratories in Murray Hill, New Jersey, USA, in the early 1980’s. Stroustrup’s C with Classes became C++ in 1983, the ‘++’ denoting the Increment Operator in C. The programming language can run on a number of platforms like Windows, Mac OS and numerous versions of UNIX.</description></item><item><title>Merge Sort</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/merge-sort/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/merge-sort/</guid><description>Merge sort is a popular sorting algorithm which uses divide and conquer algorithm. Consider an array A to be sorted. We divide the array A into two parts and sort them individually. The heart of the Merge Sort is a procedure called Merge. Let&amp;rsquo;s see the Merge procedure first and then we will use Merge as a subroutine to implement Merge Sort algorithm.
Merge Procedure Here sub-array_1 A[p,q] and sub-array-2 A[q+1,r] are sorted individually and we want to sort them as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Tree Data Structure</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/tree-data-structure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/tree-data-structure/</guid><description>Data structures are different ways in which we can store or organise data. They can be classified into broadly two types.
1. Linear Data Structures Data structures in which data is stored in the sequential arrangement are called linear data structures. For example arrays, linked lists, queues etc. Please note that this does not imply storing data in consecutive locations. Data can be stored anywhere in the memory, though the linked list is a linear data structure, it does not store data in contiguous memory locations.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - Groupby and Aggregate</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter4/</guid><description>%matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) # Make the graphs a bit prettier plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 5) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;font.family&amp;#39;] = &amp;#39;sans-serif&amp;#39; # This is necessary to show lots of columns in pandas 0.12. # Not necessary in pandas 0.13. pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.width&amp;#39;, 5000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;, 60) Okay! We&amp;rsquo;re going back to our bike path dataset here. I live in Montreal, and I was curious about whether we&amp;rsquo;re more of a commuter city or a biking-for-fun city &amp;ndash; do people bike more on weekends, or on weekdays?</description></item><item><title>Binary Search Tree</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/binary-search-tree/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/binary-search-tree/</guid><description>Previous article gave the Introduction to Trees and BST. This article will explain some important operations on BST.
Binary Search Trees are special types of binary trees where the value of every node in the left subtree is less than the value of the root node as well as the value of every node in the right subtree is greater than the value of the root node.
Structure Structure of a BST node is like following:</description></item><item><title>Calculating Average (Mean, Median, Mode) in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/average-mean-median-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/average-mean-median-mode/</guid><description>Statistics is a branch of mathematics that deals with numerical data analysis. Statistics is the study of the collection, analysis, organization, interpretation and presentation of data.
R language has been an excellent tool for statistical computation of data which includes statistical modeling, data oriented strategies and use of probability distribution and randomization in analysis. R provides various tools and functions to perform the statistical analysis of data with ease.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Variance in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/variance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/variance/</guid><description>In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to calculate Variance in R.
Variance is defined as the sum of squares of deviations of the set of numbers from the mean value. It is a measure of how far a set of data are dispersed out from their mean value . It is always a non -negative number. It is generally denoted by sigma squared σ2 (sigma squared) Where
x = Data set values µ = Mean value N = Total number of observations Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at an example that we considered for calculation of mean 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, 15.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Standard Deviation in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/standard-deviation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/standard-deviation/</guid><description>In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to calculate Standard Deviation in R.
It is a measure of spread of statistical data from its mean or average value. It determines how the data is deviated from its central value. In mathematical terms, it is simply defined as the square root of the variance and is denoted by σ.
The smallest value of the standard deviation is zero since it cannot be negative.</description></item><item><title>Generics in Java</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/java/generics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/java/generics/</guid><description>Generics in Java is the facility which is provided to the user to make a single method or single class that can be compatible with any data type like a single method can operate on integer type or string type or even object type. If you are familiar with template in C++, then you can consider generics as a template in Java. In simple words, generic methods(or classes) are those methods that are written with single method declaration and can be called or accessed with arguments of different type.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5 - Web scraping with Pandas</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter5/</guid><description>%matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 3) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;font.family&amp;#39;] = &amp;#39;sans-serif&amp;#39; Summary By the end of this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;re going to have downloaded all of Canada&amp;rsquo;s weather data for 2012, and saved it to a CSV.
We&amp;rsquo;ll do this by downloading it one month at a time, and then combining all the months together.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the temperature every hour for 2012!</description></item><item><title>Binary Search</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/binary-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/data-structures-algorithms/binary-search/</guid><description>Generally if we are asked to perform searching, what we do is take every element one by one and compare with the input value. This in computing terms is called Linear Search.
But do we really need to compare to every element in, specially in cases where number of elements are huge?
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of dictionary. Now we know that a dictionary contains thousands of words, and if we are required to search a particular word, we don&amp;rsquo;t go scanning every word in dictionary, but follow a planned approach and get towards the required word.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - String Operations</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter6/</guid><description>%matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;figure.figsize&amp;#39;] = (15, 3) plt.rcParams[&amp;#39;font.family&amp;#39;] = &amp;#39;sans-serif&amp;#39; We saw earlier that pandas is really good at dealing with dates. It is also amazing with strings! We&amp;rsquo;re going to go back to our weather data from Chapter 5, here.
weather_2012 = pd.read_csv(&amp;#39;weather_2012.csv&amp;#39;, parse_dates=True, index_col=&amp;#39;Date/Time&amp;#39;) weather_2012[:5] Output:
Temp (C) Dew Point Temp (C) Rel Hum (%) Wind Spd (km/h) Visibility (km) Stn Press (kPa) Weather Date/Time 2012-01-01 00:00:00 -1.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Cleanup messy data</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter7/</guid><description># The usual preamble import pandas as pd # Make the graphs a bit prettier, and bigger pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.mpl_style&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;default&amp;#39;) figsize(15, 5) # Always display all the columns pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.line_width&amp;#39;, 5000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;, 60) One of the main problems with messy data is: how do you know if it&amp;rsquo;s messy or not?
We&amp;rsquo;re going to use the NYC 311 service request dataset again here, since it&amp;rsquo;s big and a bit unwieldy.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 8 - Parsing Unix timestamps</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/pandas-cookbook/chapter8/</guid><description>8.1 Parsing Unix timestamps It&amp;rsquo;s not obvious how to deal with Unix timestamps in pandas &amp;ndash; it took me quite a while to figure this out. The file we&amp;rsquo;re using here is a popularity-contest file I found on my system at /var/log/popularity-contest.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an explanation of how this file works.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to hope that nothing in it is sensitive :)
import pandas as pd # Read it, and remove the last row popcon = pd.</description></item></channel></rss>