<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on TutsWiki Beta</title>
    <link>http://tutswiki.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on TutsWiki Beta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tutswiki.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment Passing in Clojure</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/environment-passing-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/environment-passing-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Clojure’s vars provide a nice mechanism for managing dynamically bound state, but you need to be careful with vars when moving computations across thread boundaries. For example, suppose we implement the following timeout function:
(import &#39;(java.util.concurrent Future TimeUnit)) (defn timeout1 [millis op] (.get (future-call op) millis TimeUnit/MILLISECONDS))  The function timeout1 sends the operation op to be computed in a separate, timeout-bound thread. If the operation completes within millis milliseconds, timeout1 returns the result of that operation, otherwise it throws an exception:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another lousy monad tutorial</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/yet-another-lousy-monad-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/yet-another-lousy-monad-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of monads, but I understand them. They&amp;rsquo;re not rocket science. Let me try to write a monad tutorial that would&amp;rsquo;ve helped my past self understand what the fuss was about. I like concrete explanations that start with practical examples, without any annoying metaphors, and especially without any Haskell code. So here&amp;rsquo;s five examples that have something in common:
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix sudo node command not found error</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/how-to-fix-sudo-node-command-not-found-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/how-to-fix-sudo-node-command-not-found-error/</guid>
      <description>Getting permission errors when installing a module?
Are &amp;lsquo;sudo: node: command not found&amp;rsquo; errors taking away your precious sleeping hours?
How to fix? You have to remove any trace of node on your system, and reinstall it. It will soothe your pain:
echo &#39;export PATH=$HOME/local/bin:$PATH&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc . ~/.bashrc mkdir ~/local &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ~/node-latest-install &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ~/node-latest-install curl http://nodejs.org/dist/node-latest.tar.gz | tar xz --strip-components=1 ./configure --prefix=~/local &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install curl https://npmjs.org/install.sh | sh rm -rf ~/node-latest-install  You are one/two steps/commands away from success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A REST API in Clojure</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/rest-api-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/rest-api-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Clojure is one of the most interesting new languages targeting the JVM. Initially only the JVM, in the meantime it is also available for JavaScript. Essentially, you can write Clojure and either execute it as Java program or JavaScript program, of course each flavor has its unique features as well.
Clojure is a Lisp, thus the syntax may be foreign, but it is really, really easy since there are very few syntactic variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract classes and interfaces in Python</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/abstract-classes-and-interfaces-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/abstract-classes-and-interfaces-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Abstract base classes and interfaces are entities that are similar in purpose and meaning. Both the first and second are a peculiar way of documenting the code and help to limit (decouple) the interaction of individual abstractions in the program (classes).
Python is a very flexible language. One facet of this flexibility is the possibilities provided by metaprogramming. And although abstract classes and interfaces are not represented in the core of the language, the former were implemented in the standard abc module, and the latter in the Zope project (the zope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deep Learning Helped Reducing Variability in Cardiovascular Imaging</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/deep-learning-cardiovascular-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/deep-learning-cardiovascular-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Bay Labs, a San Francisco-based medical technology company which focuses on using artificial intelligence to improve cardiovascular imaging, has released a new software EchoMD AutoEF. It is being claimed that this software will help to reduce the variability in cardiovascular imaging.
The software uses deep learning techniques to accurately calculate the left ventricular ejection fraction.
What is Ejection Fraction? During each pumping cycle of our heart, it contracts and relaxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Engineers Boycott Against Security Tool for Military</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/google-engineers-boycott-security-tool-military/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/google-engineers-boycott-security-tool-military/</guid>
      <description>A group of 9 cloud engineers at Google has refused to work on a project called air-gap due to which Google may lose a deal worth $10 billion. Google needs air-gap if it has to do some sensitive work with government agencies involving sensitive data (obviously military implications there). So this group of 9 basically just said they weren&amp;rsquo;t gonna do it. About 10-12 employees have resigned so far as part of this work strike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy Node.js app on Google App Engine</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/nodejs-google-app-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/nodejs-google-app-engine/</guid>
      <description>Google App Engine is a part of the Google Cloud Suite which provides a cloud platform for developers where they can develop and host their apps. It provides easily configurable, fast and secure programming environments/tools with the help of which developers can setup a development environment in just a few minutes. Therefore developers don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about configuring the environment, they can just focus on writing code. It supports all the popular programming languages Java, PHP, Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Angular 6 (Features List)</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</guid>
      <description>Angular 6 is out with all new features. It is a major release in which Angular team has synchronized many of the important framework packages to make most out of cross compatibility. All the major framework packages like @angular/core, @angular/compiler, @angular/common etc., are reworked and released as version 6.0.0. Below is the list of major changes in Angular 6, let&amp;rsquo;s explore them one by one.
Angular 6 Features:  New CLI commands  ng update ng add  Referencing providers Angular Elements Angular Material + CDK Components  Tree Badge Bottom-Sheet Overlay  Starter Components  Dashboard Side-Nav Datatable  Library Support CLI Workspaces RxJS v6 Long Term Support  ng update A new command is introduced in Angular CLI which analyzes package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Alternatives (Free, Paid, Self-Hosted)</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/github-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/github-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>The trending news of yesterday was the acquisition of GitHub (the world&amp;rsquo;s leading software development platform) by Microsoft. This is a great deal for Microsoft which might put it in the position it was about 10 years ago in the software market. But a lot of open-source fans are unhappy with this.
A couple of years ago Microsoft was anti-open-source.
 &amp;ldquo;Open source is an intellectual-property destroyer. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine something that could be worse than this for the software business and the intellectual-property business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the use of yield in Python?</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/what-is-the-use-of-yield-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/what-is-the-use-of-yield-in-python/</guid>
      <description> References  What does the “yield” keyword do in Python? Yield expressions  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference between append and extend in Python</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/append-vs-extend-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/append-vs-extend-python/</guid>
      <description>append and extend are list methods in Python which can be used to combine multiple lists. But what is the difference between them? When should you use one over another, let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
The official documentation describes them as:
 list.append(x): Add an item to the end of the list; equivalent to a[len(a):] = [x].
 list.extend(L): Extend the list by appending all the items in the given list; equivalent to a[len(a):] = L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to print on same line with print in Python</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/print-same-line-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/print-same-line-python/</guid>
      <description>In Python, when you use the print function, it prints a new line at the end.
For example:
print &amp;quot;This is some line.&amp;quot; print &amp;quot;This is another line.&amp;quot;  Output:
This is some line. This is another line.  What if you want to avoid the newline and want to print both statements on same line? Well, there are 2 possible solutions.
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing and Reading config files in Python</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-python/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure you must be aware about the importance of configuration files. Config files help creating the initial settings for any project, they help avoiding the hardcoded data.
Imagine if you migrate your server to a new host and suddenly your application stops working, now you have to go through your code and search/replace IP address of host at all the places. Config file comes to the rescue in such situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a Python module as script?</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/run-module-as-script-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/run-module-as-script-python/</guid>
      <description>Suppose you have a module named mymath.py, which has a couple of functions. You can import this module in your script and call these functions.
def int_sum(a, b): print a+b def some_other_function(): pass  But, what if you want to run the module itself as a script?
Well, if you want to use a Python module as script then you just have to use the conditional for __name__.
def int_sum(a, b): print a+b if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;: import sys int_sum(int(sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is if __name__ == &#34;__main__&#34; in Python?</title>
      <link>http://tutswiki.com/if-name-main-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tutswiki.com/if-name-main-in-python/</guid>
      <description>If you are new to Python then you may have noticed if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot; line in some python codes.
You may be wondering:
 What does that mean? What purpose does it serve? I don&amp;rsquo;t see it in all Python codes, so when should I use it exactly? Can you give me some examples?  Let me try to explain the above to you.
In Python all modules have some built-in attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>