<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C++ on TutsWiki Beta</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/</link><description>Recent content in C++ on TutsWiki Beta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction Bjarne Stroustrup, a C and Simula67 enthusiast, thought of combining the best of both the languages, and subsequently, C++ emanated at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Laboratories in Murray Hill, New Jersey, USA, in the early 1980’s. Stroustrup’s C with Classes became C++ in 1983, the ‘++’ denoting the Increment Operator in C. The programming language can run on a number of platforms like Windows, Mac OS and numerous versions of UNIX.</description></item><item><title>C++ Installation and Environment Setup</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/installation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/installation/</guid><description>C++ is a general-purpose programming language that is popularly used worldwide. C++ is efficient in terms of both memory and performance that makes it handy in competitive programming. C++ provides features like reusability of code, abstraction, polymorphism, inheritance, etc.
C++ can be run on many platforms like Linux, Windows and macOS. To start coding we need to first set up the environment to compile and run our C++ programs. We can also use online IDEs for the compilation if we don&amp;rsquo;t want to set up the environment locally.</description></item><item><title>Functions in C++</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/functions/</guid><description>What is a function? A function is a set of instructions defined by a programmer to perform a specific task. Suppose if there is a task that is to be performed multiple times in a program, so we can define the task in a function and we can call this function every time we need to use that task.
General format of a function Return_type function_name(parameter_type parameter_name) { Code; } Parts of a function Return type: This tells about the type of value that will be returned from the function.</description></item><item><title>Multithreading in C++</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/multithreading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/cplusplus/multithreading/</guid><description>What is multithreading Multithreading enables us to do parallel computing efficiently by creating multiple threads of a single process. It is used for maximum utilization of the central processing unit by concurrently executing multiple parts of a program. These parts of the program are threads.
A process can be taken as an instance of a program that is being executed by one or more threads. When a program starts, it is loaded with an address space in the main memory from the hard disk.</description></item></channel></rss>