<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>angular on TutsWiki Beta</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/tags/angular/</link><description>Recent content in angular on TutsWiki Beta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutswiki.com/tags/angular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing and Reading config files in Angular</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-angular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/read-write-config-files-in-angular/</guid><description>Ever wondered where to store configurations in your code? The most common case is to store environment configurations which are required when you have multiple environments - local, dev, qa, uat and prod. Well this article will tell you how to write and read config files in Angular. There is a defined place for storing them and you should make most use of it. But before going to that let&amp;rsquo;s check out the wrong places to store the configs.</description></item><item><title>What's new in Angular 6 (Features List)</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/angular6-features/</guid><description>Angular 6 is out with all new features. It is a major release in which Angular team has synchronized many of the important framework packages to make most out of cross compatibility. All the major framework packages like @angular/core, @angular/compiler, @angular/common etc., are reworked and released as version 6.0.0. Below is the list of major changes in Angular 6, let&amp;rsquo;s explore them one by one.
Angular 6 Features: New CLI commands ng update ng add Referencing providers Angular Elements Angular Material + CDK Components Tree Badge Bottom-Sheet Overlay Starter Components Dashboard Side-Nav Datatable Library Support CLI Workspaces RxJS v6 Long Term Support ng update A new command is introduced in Angular CLI which analyzes package.</description></item></channel></rss>