<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on TutsWiki Beta</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on TutsWiki Beta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutswiki.com/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/introduction/</guid><description>What is R? R is a programming language that is gaining its importance in software development, machine learning and data science. R is free and open source software under GNU General public license and pre-compiled binary versions and libraries are also provided for various operating systems like MAC, Linux and Windows. R provides a software environment for Statistical Modeling of data, Exploratory Data Analysis, Graphics Representation and Reproducible Researches.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Average (Mean, Median, Mode) in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/average-mean-median-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/average-mean-median-mode/</guid><description>Statistics is a branch of mathematics that deals with numerical data analysis. Statistics is the study of the collection, analysis, organization, interpretation and presentation of data.
R language has been an excellent tool for statistical computation of data which includes statistical modeling, data oriented strategies and use of probability distribution and randomization in analysis. R provides various tools and functions to perform the statistical analysis of data with ease.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Variance in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/variance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/variance/</guid><description>In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to calculate Variance in R.
Variance is defined as the sum of squares of deviations of the set of numbers from the mean value. It is a measure of how far a set of data are dispersed out from their mean value . It is always a non -negative number. It is generally denoted by sigma squared σ2 (sigma squared) Where
x = Data set values µ = Mean value N = Total number of observations Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at an example that we considered for calculation of mean 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, 15.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Standard Deviation in R</title><link>https://tutswiki.com/r/standard-deviation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutswiki.com/r/standard-deviation/</guid><description>In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to calculate Standard Deviation in R.
It is a measure of spread of statistical data from its mean or average value. It determines how the data is deviated from its central value. In mathematical terms, it is simply defined as the square root of the variance and is denoted by σ.
The smallest value of the standard deviation is zero since it cannot be negative.</description></item></channel></rss>